A Finding Aid to the Abbott Handerson Thayer and Thayer Family Papers, 1851-1999 (bulk 1881-1950), in the Archives of American Art AAA.thayabbo
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1867-1987; Series 2; (Box 1-3; 2.0 linear feet)
  - Emma Beach Thayer Correspondence, 1865-1924; 2.2
    This subseries contains the correspondence of Emma Beach Thayer, also known as Addie by her family, and document her personal life, family relationships, and management of Abbott Thayer's legacy. Found here is a large amount of correspondence with family members, including her step-daughters Mary and Gladys, her step-son Gerald, as well as her parents, sisters, nephews, nieces, and other extended family. Also found is extensive correspondence with her friend, and Thayer's first wife, Kate Bloede Thayer. Much of her correspondence is with the same people who corresponded with Abbott Thayer, but also includes other friends, most notably, Henry Ward Beecher.
    After 1916 Emma managed much of Abbott Thayer's correspondence due to his poor health, and included here are a few letters regarding the sale or exhibition of his artwork. Many of the letters found here are condolences to Emma after Abbott's death in 1921, including many letters from artists and friends expressing thoughts and memories of his life. There are also letters from Emma to many of Abbott's friends requesting his letters or copies of his for a planned book of Thayer's correspondence.
    Researchers should note that correspondence between Emma and Abbott is arranged in subseries 2.1. Emma's correspondence is arranged alphabetically by last name and chronologically within each folder.
    - A, 1905, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 77)
      Addams, Jane
      Allen, Glover M.
      Allen, Irene C.
      Allen, Nellie Wright
      American Federation of Arts
      Andrews, Robert D.
      Atlantic Monthly
      Ayres, Philip W.
    - Beach, Moses S. & Chloe (parents), 1865-1866, 1870, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Beach, William & Mabel, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1870-1883; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 80-81)
    - Benson, Frank W., 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Birch, Mary Thayer, 1891-1923; (7 folders) (Box 1, Folder 83-89)
    - Ba-Bi, 1878, 1914-1922 (Box 1, Folder 90)
      Backhouse, Irene
      Barker, Virgil
      Bartsch, Paul
      Bayard, Mabel
      Beach, Ella
      Beatty, Mr.
      Beaulieu, Bessie Price
      Bigelow, Henry B.
    - Bl-Bu, 1917-1923 (Box 1, Folder 91)
      Bowditch, Nancy
      Bowditch, Vincent Y.
      Brackett, Mary A.
      Bradley, Susan H.
      Brown, Demetra & Kenneth
      Browne, George & Emily H.
      Brush, George de Forest
    - Clemens, Samuel, circa 1880s, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Cortissoz, Royal, 1917, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - C, 1917-1922 (Box 1, Folder 94)
      Carr, W. S.
      Churchill, Alfred
      Coffin, Grace P.
      Cole, Kate Foote
      Cole, Timothy
      Curtis, Benjamin
    - Dow, Thomas Millie, 1884-1888 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - D-E, circa 1900-1922 (Box 1, Folder 96)
      Dewing, Maria Oakey
      Dickerson, Roy E.
      Dow, Florence E.
      Elliot, Mary
      Emerson, Annie S.
      Emerson, Edward W.
    - Freer, Charles L., 1915-1918 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - French, Daniel Chester, 1917-1922 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Fuertes, Louis Agassiz, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - F, 1907-1923 (Box 1, Folder 100)
      Field, Mary D.
      Forbes, Alexander
      Foster, Ben
      Freer Gallery of Art
      Fuller, Lucie Fairchild
    - Gellatly, John, 1917-1922; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - G, 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Gab__?, Clara C.
      Gould, Laura Stedman
      Goodnow, W. L.
      Gulick, Alida Carey
    - H, 1916-1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Hassam, Childe
      Hawthorne, Marion
      Historical Press Association
      Holt, Florence F.
      Houghton Mifflin Company
    - James, William & Alice, 1921-1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - J-L, 1906-1927 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Jenkins, Elizabeth F.
      John Lane Company
      Kent, Rockwell
      Keyes, Alicia
      Kittredge, S. Dana
      Low, Will H.
    - M, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Macbeth, Robert W.
      MacKaye, Percy
      Masefield, J.
      Mason, John?
      McIlvane, William M.
      Merriman, Charlotte B.
      Morris, Harrison S.
    - N-P, 1918-1924 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      National Association of Audubon Societies
      Of, George Ferdinand
      Pabrelivitsch?, Mme. Ossip
      Pevey?, Eustace
      Powell, Caroline
      Powers, Henrietta
      Putnam, James J.
    - Reasoner, David, 1920-1924 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Reasoner, Gladys Thayer, 1910-1923; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
    - Reasoner, Gladys Thayer, Undated Letters, circa 1910-1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Rice, James Henry, 1921-1924 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - R-S, 1913-1924 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Reilly, Mary S.
      Roosevelt, Edith K.
      Sainsbury, Grace E.
      Sargent, John Singer
      Sears, Mrs.
      Sharman, John
      Shurtleff, Clara E.
      Slack, Julia
      Smart, Ann Wentworth
      Smith, Annie Morrill
      Smith, H. A. Hammond
      Stillman, Evangeline
      Stone, Ellen J.
    - Thayer, Gerald H., 1917, 1921-1923; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Thayer, Kate Bloede, 1881-1887; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
    - Thayer, Kate Bloede, Undated Letters, circa 1881-1887 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - T-V, 1891, 1908-1924 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Thayer, Dr. William & Ellen Handerson
      Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service
      Troccoli, Giovanni B.
      Twitchill?, Charlotte H. P.
      Van Loon, Elize Bowditch
      Von Villern, Wilhelmina
      Vose, Robert C.
    - Whelpley, Jay & Philip, 1905-1924; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 28-32)
    - Whelpley, Jay & Philip, Undated Letters, circa 1905-1924 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - W-Y, 1916-1924 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Walker, Henry O.
      War Office, London
      Wheeler, Emma H.
      White, Lawrence Grant
      Whiting, Sue Thayer
      Whiting, Winifred Harris
      Whitney, Douglas
      Wister, Owen
      Wyeth, Annie W.
    - Unidentified Correspondents, 1867-1923 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Kate Bloede Thayer Correspondence, 1881-1889; 2.3
    Kate Bloede Thayer's correspondence documents family activities and friendships during the 1880s. Included are letters in German from her grandfather, letters from her brother, Victor, and several letters from her daughter Mary sent during Kate's time at a sanatorium. Also found are letters from artist friends including Arthur Bell, Thomas Millie Dow, and Lewis T. Ives. Dow's letters discuss his travels in Europe, his current artwork, mutual friends such as Arthur Bell, and other general news. Ives's letters also discuss mutual friends and general news. Letters from Kate to her in-laws, William and Ellen Thayer, discuss family news and news of Abbot's work. Other correspondence, arranged alphabetically, contains letters from family and friends. Correspondence between Kate Bloede Thayer and Emma Beach Thayer is found with Emma Beach's correspondence.
    - Bloede, Grandpa, 1881-1884 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bloede, Victor, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Birch, Mary Thayer, 1888-1889 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Dow, Thomas Millie, 1881-1886 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Ives, Lew. T., 1882-1888 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Thayer, Dr. William & Ellen Handerson, 1881-1887; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 41-43)
    - B-H, 1882-1888 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - M-S, 1887-1889 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified letter fragments, 1880s (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Gladys Thayer Reasoner Correspondence, 1907-1943; 2.4
    The correspondence of Gladys Thayer Reasoner, a.k.a Galla, documents family activities and her friendships. Found here are letters to and from family members, including her sister Mary, her brother Gerald (known as Gra), nephews, nieces, and other extended family, such as her cousins in the Foster and Whiting families. Additional letters are from friends, including Randolph Bourne, Frances Burns, Evangeline Stillman, Blanche Walton, and others. Gladys also maintained correspondence with Thayer family friends, who were friends of her parents, or members of the Dublin, New Hampshire community in which they lived, such as Mary Amory Greene, John Gellatly, Richard Meryman, Raphael Pumpelly, and Jay and Philip Whelpley. Gladys' correspondence is also found in the subseries containing her father and stepmother Emma Beach Thayer correspondence.
    - Birch, Elsie, 1916-1936 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Birch, Mary Thayer, 1916-1927 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Bourne, Randolph, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Buckley, Lily, 1917-1922 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Burns, Frances L., circa 1920-1935 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - B, 1912-1937 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Beach, Violet
      Beaulieu, Mary
      Berlingham, Robert
      Buckley, Lou
    - C-D, 1907-1943 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Cameron, Hugh A.
      Clemens, Jean
      Comstock, Charlie L.
      Cortissoz, Royal
      Daniels, George E.
    - Fisher, Eleanor, 1908-1922 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Fisher, Faith H. (Mrs. William F. Fenn), 1928-1936 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Fisher, Richard & Nina, 1939-1935 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - F, 1911-1935 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      F., W. W.
      Fisher, Ellen Thayer
    - G-H, 1909-1942 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Gellatly, John
      Gleason, John R.
      Goldschmidt, Anita
      Harvard College, Museum of Comparative Zoology
      Hoen, A. B.
      Hu_?, Evan
    - J, 1911-1936 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      James, Henry
      James, Nina Marion
      James, William
    - K-L, 1908-1935 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      Keane, Polla Price
      Kellogg, Foster S.
      Kittredge, Anna M.
      Kleb, Sarah M.
      Lord, Ruth Whiting
      Lowder, Isabel
    - M-O, 1922-1937 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      MacVeagh, Eames
      Martin, Polly (Mrs. G. Rainsford Martin)
      Meryman, Richard S. (Wig)
      Nautilus Beach Club
      Ohta family
    - Palmer, H. P., 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - P, 1911-1937 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      Page, Arthur W.
      Paramount Pictures Distributing Corporation
      Percy, Eustace
      Pinkham, M.
      Public Works of Art Project
      Pumpelly, Raphael
      Putnam, Shirley
    - Reasoner, David, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - R, 1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Reasoner, Mrs. (David's Mother)
      Reasoner, Nan
      Rodakiewicz, Eva
    - Stillman, Michael & Evangeline, 1909-1935 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - S, 1911, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 67)
      Schurmeier, Theodora
      Stokes, Rose Paxton
    - Thayer, Gerald H., 1908-1936 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - T, 1911-1941 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      Tax Commissioner
      Thayer, Alma
      Thayer, Bernie
      Tish, Hay
      Treasury Department, Public Works of Art Project
    - Walton, Blanche W., 1923-1937 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Whelpley, Jay & Philip, 1907-1937; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 71-74)
    - Whiting, Susan Thayer, 1928-1936 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - W, 1912-1943 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      W., Marion W.
      Wangler, Kathy & Albert McCreery
      War Department
      Warner, Langdon
      White, Nelson C.
      Whiting, Rose
      The Woman Citizen
      Wynne, Annette
    - First Names Only: A-H, 1912-1936 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - First Names Only: J-R, 1907-1936 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - David Reasoner Correspondence, 1918-1954; 2.5
    David Reasoner's correspondence is primarily with family and friends, such as Emma Beach Thayer's sister, Violet, and from Mary Thayer Birch discussing Emma's estate, Gerald's ill health, and other family news. David Reasoner also corresponded with John Gellatly concerning the sale of Abbott Thayer's paintings, and with Gerald Thayer concerning financial matters. Other alphabetical correspondence is with Thayer and Reasoner family members, people working on books or requesting information on Abbott Thayer, museums exhibiting Thayer's work, and people interested in purchasing artwork by Thayer. Also found are letters concerning the deaths of Reasoner's mother, his wife Gladys, and his son Allen. The bulk of the David Reasoner correspondence concerning the estates of Abbott H. Thayer and Emma Beach Thayer is found in Series 4: Estate Papers.
    - Beach, Violet, 1924-1932 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Birch, Mary Thayer, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Gellatly, John, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Thayer, Gerald, 1922-1930 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - A-B, 1921-1949 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - C-D, 1925, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - F-G, 1924-1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - H-J, 1925-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - L-P, 1922-1936, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - R, 1924-1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - T-V, 1918, 1943-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - W, 1928-1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, 1942-1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1883-1987; 2.6
    This series contains the correspondence of other members of the Thayer and Reasoner families. Included is correspondence between Elsie Birch and her cousins, and the correspondence of her mother, Mary Thayer Birch. Also found are letters to Jean Reasoner Plunket, Abbott Thayer's granddaughter, including many from Nelson C. White, who collected research material for a biography of Abbott Thayer.
    Gerald H. Thayer's correspondence discusses concealing coloration, the estate of Abbott and Emma Thayer, and letters of condolence from George Gray Barnard and Edwin H. Blashfield. Additional correspondence found here includes letters to Gerald's wife, Alma, from the family friend and Thayer patron, John Gellatly, letters to Abbott Thayer's parents, Dr. William and Ellen Thayer, and letters to Jay and Philip Whelpley, family friends of the Thayers.
    - Elsie Birch, 1933, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Mary Thayer Birch, 1886-1915, circa 1924 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Jean Reasoner Plunket, 1945-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Allen Reasoner, 1935-1942 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Alma E. Thayer from John Gellatly, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Gerald H. Thayer, 1908-1924 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dr. William H. Thayer and Ellen Handerson Thayer, 1883-1891 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Jay and Philip Whelpley, 1910-1927 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1908-1927 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Writings, 1888-1945; Series 3; (Box 3-4; 0.8 linear feet)
  This series contains writings by Abbott Handerson Thayer and others, including family members and scholars. Writings by Thayer primarily focus on his theories about concealing coloration and nature observations through notes and draft writings. Also found are his writings on other topics such as the restoration of artwork. Writings by others include the writings of Emma Beach Thayer and Abbott Thayer's daughters Mary and Gladys, and writings by scholars about the Thayer's artwork.
  The Writings series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  Subseries 3.1: Writings by Abbott Handerson Thayer, circa 1890-1918
  Subseries 3.2: Writings by Others, 1888-1989
  - Writings by Abbott Handerson Thayer, circa 1890-1918; 3.1
    Writings by Abbott Handerson Thayer, primarily on the topic of concealing coloration and his observations of nature, include four small notebooks. His notes and draft essays, often written on small scraps of paper or the back of other documents, are on the topic of concealing coloration in nature, and the related topics, the invisibility of icebergs and the concealing coloration in military uniforms and warships. Many of his notes appear to be preparations for lectures or letters to the editor on these topics, or responses to the negative feedback from his book Concealing Coloration in Nature, published in 1909. Also found are draft essays on the restoration of works of art and notes and essays on various subjects such as the Boer war, art, and other thoughts on nature.
    - Notebooks, circa 1890-1920; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - Notes & Essays on Concealing Coloration in Nature, circa 1910-1917; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 20-23)
    - Notes & Essays on the Invisibility of Icebergs, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Notes & Essays on Concealing Coloration in Uniforms & Warships, circa 1915-1918; (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 25-30)
    - Essay, "Restoration: The Doom of Works of Art", 1917 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Typescript, "Restoration of Pictures", circa 1910s; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 32-34)
    - Draft Letters to the Editor of The Auk, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Notes & Essays on Various Subjects, circa 1901-1919; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 36-39)
  - Writings by Others, 1888-1989; 3.2
    This subseries contains writings by the Thayer family and writings by scholars, primarily about Abbott Handerson Thayer. Included are writings by Emma Thayer, such as a manuscript for a story entitiled "Ernest" and two poems, and Mary Thayer's diary and corresponding hand-made calendar, written when she was ten years old. Writings by Gladys Thayer Reasoner include a brief biographical sketch of her father, a biography of her son, Allen Reasoner, who died in 1943 in a plane crash, and stories and other writings she wrote as a young girl.
    Writings by others about Abbott Thayer include a draft manuscript by Nancy Bell, wife of artist Arthur Bell, about Thayer's book on concealing coloration. This series also contains writings by unidentified authors, such as draft writings about George Gray Barnard, possibly written by David or Gladys Thayer Reasoner, and miscellaneous writings and poetry by others. Folders are arranged by author and title of work, if known, and chronologically within each folder.
    - Emma Beach Thayer, "Ernest", circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Emma Beach Thayer, Poetry, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Mary Thayer, Diary and Calendar, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Gladys Thayer Reasoner, Biographical Sketch of Abbott H. Thayer, circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Gladys Thayer Reasoner, Biography of Allen Reasoner, "One Out of Fifty", circa 1945 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Gladys Thayer Reasoner, Biography of Allen Reasoner, Draft Versions, circa 1945; (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 45-47)
    - Gladys Thayer Reasoner, Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1897 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Sidney Allen, "Abbott Handerson Thayer: An Appreciation of His Work", circa 1920s (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Nancy Bell, "A Painter Naturalist and His Son", circa 1909 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - William Dutcher, "Report of the A. O. U. Committee on the Protection of North American Birds for the Year 1903" (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Elizabeth Walmsley, "A Preliminary Investigation into the Painting Techniquest of Abbott Handerson Thayer", 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Unknown Author, Notes for a Book on Abbott H. Thayer, circa 1920s (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Unknown Author, Lecture on Rembrandt and Reubens, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Unknown Author, Writings about George Grey Barnard, circa 1938 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous Writings by Others, circa 1890-1920 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Poetry, circa 1900-1945; (Partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Estate Papers, 1921-1954; Series 4; (Box 4; 0.5 linear feet)
  This series contains the estate papers for Abbott Handerson Thayer, who died in 1921 and Emma Beach Thayer, who died in 1924. Much of material consists of correspondence between David Reasoner, Executor of both estates, and others regarding financial and legal matters. Correspondence of note is with Mary and Gerald Thayer regarding their inheritance, and with E. & A. Milch, Inc. and William Macbeth, Inc. regarding the sale of artwork. Also found are financial and legal documents, forms, lists and notes, and Emma Thayer's will and drafts. Some of the financial account statements and a ledger book have not been scanned.
  Items are arranged chronologically within each folder.
  - Estate Papers of Abbott H. Thayer and Emma B. Thayer, 1921-1924; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
  - Estate Papers of Abbott H. Thayer and Emma B. Thayer, 1925-1954; (13 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-18)
  - Emma Beach Thayer Last Will and Testament, 1923, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Estate Account Statements, Kingston Trust Company, 1927-1932; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Estate Bills, 1922-1938; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - Ledger Book for Emma Thayer Estate, 1924-1925; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Other Financial Records, 1889-1957; Series 5; (Box 4; 7 folders)
  This series contains a small amount of Thayer and Reasoner family financial records not directly related to the estates of Abbott or Emma Thayer. Most of this series has not been scanned.
  - Account Statements, 1924-1941; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bills & Receipts, 1889-1919; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Liberty Bonds, Cheshire National Bank, 1919-1921; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Ledger, 1923-1935 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Ledger kept by Emma Beach Thayer, 1915-1923 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Ledger kept by David Reasoner, 1921-1930; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - David Reasoner Bethesda Country Club Membership, 1948-1957; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Legal Records, 1891-1927; Series 6; (Box 4; 4 folders)
  Legal records include a copy of the patent office record given to Gerome Brush and Abbott Handerson Thayer for the "process of treating the outsides of ships & for making them less visible." Also included in that folder is a contract handwritten by Thayer giving Brush claim to use of the original invention. Other documents in this series are legal agreements, including a draft agreement among landowners in Dublin, New Hampshire to create a nature reservation, and deeds of property belonging to Abbott Thayer and Emma Beach Thayer. Also found is a map of the property owned by Thayer and surrounding properties in Dublin.
  - Patent Documents, 1902, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Legal Agreements, 1908-1927 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Deeds of Property, 1891-1921 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Map of Thayer Property, Dublin, New Hampshire, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Printed Material, 1851, 1896-1999; Series 7; (Box 4-5; 0.4 linear feet)
  Printed material includes two books, an alphabet book belonging to Abbott Thayer which he inscribed and gave to his daughter Mary, and a bound article written by Theodore Roosevelt in response to Thayer's book on concealing coloration. The article was originally published in the Bulletin of the American Museum of Natural History, volume XXX. Also found are newspaper and magazine clippings about Abbott Thayer, about his artwork and exhibitions, and about the Reasoner family. Exhibition announcements and catalogs are for exhibitions by Thayer, his daughter Gladys Thayer Reasoner, and group exhibitions. Other material in this series is about the Woodstock Playhouse, for which David Reasoner was the director, and includes news clippings, programs and newsletters, and the publication Hue and Cry.
  - Book, Illustrated Alphabet of Animals, 1851; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Book, Revealing and Concealing Coloration in Birds and Mammals, by Theodore Roosevelt, 1911, (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Clippings, 1900-1996; (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 38-42)
  - Clippings about Woodstock Playhouse, circa 1929-1949; (Not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1896-1983; (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 44-49)
  - Newsletters & Event Calendars, 1980-1983, 1999; (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters & Programs from Woodstock, New York, 1928-1941; (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hue and Cry Newspaper, 1925, 1928, 1929; (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1895, 1914-circa 1966; (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Photographs, circa 1861-1933; Series 8; (Box 5, MGP 2; 0.2 linear feet)